ABID HUSSAIN ANJUM

Work Authorization: Visa required except Saudi Arabia

Current Residence: Riyadh Saudi Arabia

Nationality: Pakistani

Mobile No: +966 56 5663825 Email: abid.anjum.sa2019@gmail.com

DOB: 15 Feb 1979

Linked In: www.linkedin.com/in/abid-anjum-8371a517b

GitHub: https://github.com/abid-anjum **Website**: https://abid-anjum.github.io

YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrAgca7Zc2Z7pwNIVK-5bXA

SUMMARY

17 years hands on experience in multiple technologies, designed and developed enterprise web and mobile applications, 6 years worked as solution architect technical lead, ability to work in Parallel on multiple projects in different technologies, worked as full stack web and mobile architect/developer. Being architect design enterprise architecture for Java .Net and Mobile apps.

Good experience working in agile scrum environment.

SKILLS

Java

- Java (Spring Boot)
- J2EE
- Web Services (SOAP and Restful)
- Micro Services
- JPA (Hibernate)
- JWT Authentication/Oauth2
- Proficiency with front-end languages such as HTML, CSS, Ajax, Bootstrap, Angular 2+ and JavaScript.
- Experience in RabbitMQ and Kafka.
- Amazon Web Services experience (EC2, S3, RDS, Elastic, Cloud Front)
- Git, Maven and Gradle
- DevOps with Azure and Jenkins
- Familiarity with Dockers and Kubernetes

Mobile Apps

- Good Experience with native iOS and Android application design & development.
- Objective-C, Swift skills and inside-and-out Knowledge of the iOS SDK.
- Strong Java skills with extensive knowledge of the Android SDK.
- Strong understanding of RESTful JSON web API design principles
- Create clean interfaces and smooth interactions based on UI/UX design
- Development of Cross platform mobile applications with Cordova and React native
- Write Mobile application backend services with Java, PHP
- Experience with Apps Store and Play store
- MVC and MVVM design pattern
- Push Notification
- Backend Integration
- offline data store and sync

Microsoft .Net

- Experience in C# .NET, ASP.NET, JavaScript, JQuery, JSON, and Service Oriented Architecture.
- NET Core 2.x and .NET Framework 4.6.x
- Proficiency in Web Services and Web API.
- Experience with Angular 2x and above.
- Proficiency with ORM (Dapper/Entity Framework)
- Experience working with SQL Server, ability to write complex SQL queries.







- Experience in Domain-Driven Design (DDD).
- SharePoint development in version 2010, 2013

Databases

- Oracle, SQL Server
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- MongoDB (NoSQL)

GIS Skills

- QGIS
- Design WMS, WFS services with GeoServer
- Web portal development with Leaflet, Open Layer
- ArcGIS API for JavaScript
- Python Django

Academic Background

- Master in Computer Sciences yrs. 2004
- Microsoft Certified Professional
- Microsoft Certified Solution developer
- Java Certified Professional

Few Major Projects

1. SMOS (Smart management operation suit)

Role: As a technical lead

An enterprise web and mobile solution developed in Java, spring Boot, Angular 11, Hibernate, Android and IOS platform

2. ESDIM GIS Mobile App

Role: As a Lead Developer Architect

A GIS mobile application developed in Java android and Swift.

3. Insurance Management System

Role: As Lead Developer

A web and mobile solution developed in Asp.net MVC, C#, Angular 8, and mobile app developed in Xamarin Native (android and IOS)

4. Logistic operation and support management system

Role: As Lead Developer

A Web and mobile application solution developed in Java, prime faces, EJB, android and IOS platform

5. E-Trading (online trading complete solution)

Role: As Lead Developer

A web application developed in Java, Oracle ADF and EJB

6. Billing system

Role: As Team member

A billing system developed in Java, J2EE, spring boot, Angular2, Hibernate

7. Express Mobile App

Role: As a Lead Developer

A mobile application developed in Java android and Swift

Experience

Organization: (April 2013 - Current)

ANSCL Riyadh Saudi Arabia https://www.netsoltech.com/

<u>Designation</u>: Lead Full Stack Developer | Architect (Web and Mobile)

Roles & Responsibilities:

Understanding client requirements and Programming and develop web and mobile applications

- Produce design document based on requirement study
- Work closely with QA engineers, product managers, UXI experts and designers in order to produce top quality apps
- Work collaboratively with technical team for best technical solutions
- Work as independent and lead a team of developers
- Deploy app on client test and production system and lead UAT activity
- Work closely with product management to communicate trade-offs, alternatives, and effort, and to ensure the very best customer experience
- Take a data driven approach, and pitch in with efforts to innovate to continuously improve delivery speed and quality

Organization: (Jun 2010 to Jan 2013)

NetSol technologies Lahore Pakistan https://www.netsoltech.com/

<u>Designation</u>: Lead Mobile and web developer | Architect

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Understand client requirements and Programming and develop web and mobile applications
- Produce design document
- Lead technically develop team
- Close contact with QA department for Quality
- Deploy app on client side and provide training

Organization: (July 2009 to June 2010)

FutureNow technologies Lahore Pakistan www.fnint.com

Designation: Senior software developer

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Write code for new software and maintain existing software code, deployment on client side
- Testing & modification of code, programs, unit testing, bug fixing
- Requirement study & produce design document
- Design user guide, training to client & upgrading of legacy system
- Software technical support to client & problem resolution
- Technical guide to junior team members
- Client communication and training

Organization: (DEC 2007 - JUN 2009)

Eworx International Lahore Pakistan www.eworxintl.com

Designation: Senior software developer

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Write code for new software and maintain existing software code, deployment on client side
- Testing & modification of code, programs, unit testing, bug fixing
- Requirement study & produce design document

Organization: (JAN 2004 - NOV 2007)

Etechsol Lahore Pakistan http://www.etechsol.com/

Designation: Software developer

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Design and develop software according to customer requirement
- Write code for new software and maintain existing software code, deployment on client side
- Testing & modification of code, programs, unit testing, bug fixing